Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Huh?
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: The queen!
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Proverbs!
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Greatness for summer!
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Brow, brow, one command!
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: It's no love in the jungle.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: It's no love in the jungle. It is light, it's no love in the jungle. It's no love in the jungle. It don't do no light
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Hi, ladies!
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I was king, the queen It all died, you die.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: She's down, 6 weeks ago!
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: It is like… It's no love in the jungle.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: The jungle.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Don't live in the jungle.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Count the love in the jungle.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: No, no, no, no, no blood!
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: You are the shadow to my life.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Cause my feeling is just so right As we dance by the moonlight.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Can't you see your mountains? Lady, I just feel like I won't catch you.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Alabama!
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I feel love For the first time, and I know that it's true, I can't dead by the look in your eyes.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Lady, hit me too late, cause my feeling is just so right as we dance by the moonlight. Can't you see your mighty light? Lady!
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I just feel like I won't catch you.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I love my mind, I feel love For the first time, and I know that it's too uncounted by the look in your eyes.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Later, hear me tonight, cause my feeling, it's just so right as we dance by the moonlight Can't you see? Y'all might be light? Later, I just feel like I won't get you
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Out of my mind, I feel love For the first time, and I know that it's true, I can tell by the look in your eyes.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: forever.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I feel love the first time in my first time.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Can't you see it, to see Almighty, I might be my own real
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I won't get you, won't get
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Cause my being, I'm being just sore at a store right now.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Why wait too safe? At least I did in my way. But I wait too phased. But in my heart, I understand. I made my move, and it was all about you. Now I feel so far removed.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: You are the one thing in my way, you are the one thing in my way. You are the one thing in my way. You are the one thing in my way, you are the one thing in my way. You are the one thing in my way.
100xEngineers: Hey, hi folks, can you hear me? Can you see me?
100xEngineers: How are you guys feeling? Let's do a quick wipe check, if you can hear me clearly.
100xEngineers: Let me check if the chat is… oh, you guys can chat. Yes. Hi, Dave.
100xEngineers: How are you guys feeling? How's the week going so far?
100xEngineers: On a scale of 1 to 10.
100xEngineers: Always 100X. Wow.
100xEngineers: Awesome.
100xEngineers: 9, 5. I'll try to guess the average vibe of this room.
100xEngineers: something which I do a lot. 97889, I think it's, like, somewhere around 8.5 right now.
100xEngineers: Wow, pretty good, actually. You guys are matching the vibe. I think we can definitely…
100xEngineers: do more things apart from just lectures. I don't know how many of you are in Bangalore, planning to come to Bangalore. By the way, if you are planning to visit, definitely, check out our office, like, we stay in North Bangalore.
100xEngineers: And, yeah, like, we can vibe after the lecture as well.
100xEngineers: Awesome, that's great, Nikhil.
100xEngineers: Cool. Anyways, we'll invite you guys at the end of this journey, so… I don't know how many of you…
100xEngineers: are aware about is we do a demo day after the end of 6-month journey, but
100xEngineers: Yeah, like, I want to just, like, quickly set the agenda of today's session. One other thing which I want to start with today is the first implementation of
100xEngineers: everything that we've been learning. This is about…
100xEngineers: building UI, building systems, and especially, like, the thing which we're going to focus today is one part of the system that we started learning last week. This is the deterministic side of things.
100xEngineers: things which need an interface between a human being and a machine, so that's what we learned. That's where the user interface comes in. And user interface is not the only thing, but we have to build a whole system which
100xEngineers: has an interface that can allow a human being to interact with a machine, and then does a lot of other things as well. So, at the end of the day, what we want to do for this session, the agenda, is to build a system that can interact with a human being, and also give you some relevant output.
100xEngineers: We will take this as an example in the upcoming sessions, and we'll try to add more elements, more interfaces to it. By the end of next…
100xEngineers: I would say 2 weeks, we would have our full-fledged application ready, which you guys can deploy, share with people, that is connected to an LLM.
100xEngineers: So, if you will follow along all the lectures, including the practice sets and the assignments which I'll be sharing with all of you.
100xEngineers: I can tell you, even if you do not have the coding expertise, this is a… is a track which we have tested against, like, a lot of coders as well as non-coders. You guys will be able to, like.
100xEngineers: build your first MVP.
100xEngineers: Personally, for me, the North Star is that each and everybody who is sitting here, I would be able to help you with the three things, and the three things there is everyone should be able to understand and discover the problem statement in your
100xEngineers: Day-to-day work.
100xEngineers: Maybe it's about, say, finding one opportunity which you can automate in your job.
100xEngineers: That can help you save some time. Or maybe identifying a business process in your company that can help your company save time and increase their productivity. Or maybe finding an opportunity to, like, increase the revenue of a business, right? So these are, like, some of the examples which
100xEngineers: All of you can do. And the way how you will be doing it is using the Discovery to MVP skill. I hope, like… Can we have a quick raise of hands? How many of you have completed the Discovery to MVP skill assignment?
100xEngineers: Or at least generated the MVP plan. Let's do the MVP plan generation. How many of you have a plan right now?
100xEngineers: Which you can… Take to the next level.
100xEngineers: Okay? Just raise your hand if you have a plan ready.
100xEngineers: I'll do a quick count.
100xEngineers: Although I was expecting slightly higher number, but… Where we have… I think the… Close to, like.
100xEngineers: 15-20% of the room.
100xEngineers: Which is… Which is good, actually, but the thing is, I… I'm, again, trying to repeat this thing.
100xEngineers: the entire goal of this module is to make things more personalized to you guys, and if you don't have a problem statement right now, I will give you a random problem statement. It's not random, it's gonna be my problem statement, right? And some of you might enjoy it, some of you don't, but that won't…
100xEngineers: help you to build this entire thing in a way, like, which is gonna be very hyper-personalized to you, right? So the best way to take advantage of these sessions, as well as the exercise and the mental models, which I'll share.
100xEngineers: is to make sure that you have the discovery document ready with you. Like, you should perform an exercise. And I know, like, for some people, it's, like, difficult to start, because you might be in a state where you don't know exactly what is the problem I'm gonna solve, but just go with it. Use OPD right now.
100xEngineers: just…
100xEngineers: Try to look at the things which you do, and start from there. But, this is the mandatory requirement from next session onwards. This session is okay, even if you don't have it.
100xEngineers: You can use my example, the RF example, but from next session onward, just make sure that you have an MVP plan ready. The next… the next prerequisite before we start the session, and also for the upcoming session, is…
100xEngineers: the Python.
100xEngineers: Can you guys lower your hand raise? I'll ask the second question, so…
100xEngineers: I'll be able to, like, take the count. Just lower the hand raise people who have raised their hand previously.
100xEngineers: Okay, the question here, which I want to understand, it's a prerequisite for this session and for all the upcoming sessions, is that how many of you have completed the big binary exercises? The Python big bind exercises? Just raise the hand if you have completed the Python Big Bind Exercise.
100xEngineers: If you don't know about what I'm talking about, you can just,
100xEngineers: check this on your LMS, but I'll also share the link…
100xEngineers: Okay, we have a couple of people. We have actually a similar number of folks who have finished the MVP plan.
100xEngineers: These are the folks who are… done with Python.
100xEngineers: This is the link. If somebody has not checked it out, I would recommend you to do this. Moving forward…
100xEngineers: As I discussed previously, The best way to learn code?
100xEngineers: Is by writing code, not by watching somebody and by, like, by basically, like.
100xEngineers: understanding me, and I don't want to, like, do that, because that's not going to be the best use of my time and your time. And even if I take a 2-hour lecture, because I've taken that, like, just to give you an example, I've taken a 3-month long program where I was teaching people how to write code.
100xEngineers: And, you know, one of the insights from that entire program is that only 10% of the people were actually writing code in the sessions and also at the end of it.
100xEngineers: Which, again, makes me think, like, people don't learn by watching tutorials, they learn by building things, and that's the whole premise of it. So, two things, make sure…
100xEngineers: One is your MVP exercise, the discovery to MVP skill, you need to run that skill, the assignment number one. The second thing is the Python Big Binet. These are the two things which are important for upcoming sessions. In this session, I'll give you
100xEngineers: a clear overview, using my own example. So even if you haven't done all of this, and you'll still be able to, like.
100xEngineers: understand, I hope, majority of it. If not, you can let me know. But from the next lecture onwards, just make sure this… this happens. Now, coming back to the… you guys can lower your hand raise, by the way. I'll… I'll take the questions at the end of, actually, at the mid. Let me share my screen, and
100xEngineers: Will…
100xEngineers: Okay, I have…
100xEngineers: Let me know if you guys can see my screen.
100xEngineers: Can you? Awesome.
100xEngineers: Cool, this is a story just for everybody to… Get the context. We discussed…
100xEngineers: in week one, like Saeed Uchar mentioned.
100xEngineers: How to understand what to build.
100xEngineers: This is where the… Discovery validation and discovery to MEB skill comes in.
100xEngineers: We realized that why it is important
100xEngineers: Before doing it. The module 2 is gonna be more personalized, and we're gonna, like, learn things by solving a problem that you guys face in your day-to-day, basis, or maybe as a company, or if you're building a product.
100xEngineers: You can take that as an example. The whole point of doing this first exercise, our first assignment, is to understand that we have a problem statement, and for this problem statement, we can identify the input and the output. This is a core job, and this is the software engineering principle which I was sharing in the last lecture as well. The core job of
100xEngineers: Somebody like us, somebody who's a builder, who's an engineer, is to understand
100xEngineers: first of all, what to solve? What kind of problems are worth solving? That is what you'll learn here. And then, once you know this is a problem which is worth solving.
100xEngineers: Understanding what are the inputs.
100xEngineers: Which, as a user, whoever is using this system, they'll give it. And what is the desired output they expect? Once you have clarity on these two things, you start designing a system. And, the system covers a lot of things.
100xEngineers: on a… Higher level, three main important
100xEngineers: components and primitives here. Deterministic, probabilistic, and the human-in-the-loop part. We will start our journey from deterministic things, and in the deterministic system, the first thing which we learned is
100xEngineers: we need an interface. We had a whole discovery about the interface in this… the last lecture, the first interface which I took, and we realized that even when we work with ChatGPT, it's not just one single app which does everything.
100xEngineers: in, in, in the… backend, or maybe you can say in the whole…
100xEngineers: architecture, this is how it is split, right? Which means there's a user, like us, we put the input, in this case, the ChatGBT example, the input becomes, like, the prompt, and the output is the model output, which we have here.
100xEngineers: And in order for us to interact with it, we need a front-end, which usually runs on a browser, which is a…
100xEngineers: client's machine. In this case, it was running on my personal computer. In your case, it could be running everywhere else. And, similar to that, I'll remove this part. As of now, it's not needed.
100xEngineers: So this interaction between human to machine.
100xEngineers: is done by the interface of what we call user interface, and then we definitely need another machine which has the actual model, which can interact with this model, but we also learned that model is just a file, which predicts the next word token, so we need a system around this model that can store the information if somebody, like.
100xEngineers: close their browser, and wants to get the data back. Somebody who's logging in, somebody who's paying for the model to keep a track of subscription payments and everything. So we need a system for that, and that's where the backend comes in. And to store information, we need a data storage system. This is…
100xEngineers: Primarily can be used on files, you can use files in the data storage, you can use a fancy database as well. We'll learn more about it in the upcoming sessions. We started our journey from the first interface, so we… today we're gonna build this interface first. And the journey, how it looks like is…
100xEngineers: Once you learn that
100xEngineers: This is the thing which we are building today, and you can, like, solve this problem of, like, building this small system. Next week onwards, you can build
100xEngineers: another system, like, let's say, backend, and after that, you can build LLM, and after that, in this lecture, you can build database. So it's gonna be, like, around 1, 2, 3, 4. It'll take you 4 lectures, exactly. More or less, like, we can add, like, one or two lectures
100xEngineers: Because there are, like, few things which you need to understand. But, in the next, like.
100xEngineers: four to five lectures. We will build each and every system from scratch, from first principles, using code as an approach, that's the track you guys have opted for.
100xEngineers: And, at the end of the next two weeks, the goal for us to, like, build all of these systems and combine the whole output, so that we have our first deterministic system ready. Now, I'm saying deterministic, but we do have, like, one probabilistic element to it, although we won't touch it, like.
100xEngineers: in a deeper way, we will use LLM as another API, and I'll teach you that once we know more about it. But we would have, like, ideally a system that has elements of both probabilistic as well as deterministic, so it could look like
100xEngineers: a wrapper application, just like what ChatGPT is today. ChatGPT is not,
100xEngineers: I would say, like, anything different, but it is a wrapper around A probabilistic system.
100xEngineers: Or, I would say, in this case, Specifically, LLM, the GBT LLM.
100xEngineers: And that is what the goal for us is, first to…
100xEngineers: understand the system, and also then, at the end of it, in the next two weeks, all of you would be able to build this wrapper application. I hope that is clear, and that is the journey which we are taking in.
100xEngineers: Now, in order for me to, like, start this journey, I will continue with the exercise, and this is what I was expecting you, right? As I mentioned, like, if you have not done it, you can go to the same skill, download this skill, add it to your cloud.
100xEngineers: or codecs, or whatever you're using. And, this is a chat which I've also shared here. You can have a whole chat. At the end of this skill, you'll get two documents. This is the discovery document, which will give you the observation. In this case, my observation was ambitious early career professionals in urban India.
100xEngineers: arrive AI-aware and motivated, but when asked to convert the awareness into a specific project, they fail at selection, scoping, and first proof. They see AI opportunity at the category level, sales, automation, HR tools, productivity agent, but cannot translate that into a specific grounded workflow worth building.
100xEngineers: They skip the step of defining the user, repeated task, current process, bottlenecks, etc. So every project starts awake, becomes overwhelming, and collapses back into the consumption. The breakdown happens before building at the moment. This was my observation, which I have seen across running multiple cohorts.
100xEngineers: So I decided to, like, use this observation and see whether I can build a falsifiable hypothesis. I had some evidence in my experience, so I built a hypothesis around it.
100xEngineers: it has some condition that when this hypothesis will be successful, when it will be failed, what are the assumptions out there. And I also ran a stress test against the simulated conversation with my user, where LM was acting as a user, and I realized that there are some assumptions which I made, which got well-dated.
100xEngineers: And some assumptions got weakened. As a result of all of these things, I got some insights that what I should do, how should I test these assumptions and my hypothesis.
100xEngineers: One of the best ways to test this hypothesis is to build an MVP, right? But the problem here is we haven't learned anything, and that's one of the reasons why this MVP is a manual MVP plan, which means
100xEngineers: everything what this plan suggests to you, and if you have generated this with your skill, it would ideally tell you to perform these things, rather than building a software. In this case, the main part here was
100xEngineers: to…
100xEngineers: to understand whether the hypothesis which we have built, whether these people, like Arav, need some kind of system, and if we can build that system that can provide them value.
100xEngineers: So…
100xEngineers: This is how the MVB looks like for me. The MVB here mentions that in 21 days, RF goes from, I am learning AI, to I diagnose to one real workflow.
100xEngineers: built an AI-assisted proof of value, tested it with real users, and packaged it into a video and a demo case study. If we can help Arav to go from just
100xEngineers: something what he does right now, to something where he can actually do all of these things, that is the proof, and that is something which we are trying to do. Like, this is my problem statement, again, as I said, like, if you are somebody who falls into the category, who have not performed the discovery exercise.
100xEngineers: you can take this as an example. If you have already done that, then you can open your document right now, and you can just, like, keep the MB plan ready, as I give you the next set of instructions.
100xEngineers: Just to set the context for this particular example, I got this plan. Now, what I'm supposed to do right now, and
100xEngineers: Similarly, for your plan, whatever you have done.
100xEngineers: It would give you, like, many on…
100xEngineers: 3-4 weeks plan, in my case, it was a 21-day plan, where I have to… Perform these tasks.
100xEngineers: And there are some actions and some outputs which is written for each and every day. So I need to take these intakes, screening, questions, I need to, like, find people who
100xEngineers: who would be fit for my solution, or who I can use to validate my assumptions and hypotheses, and then, like, perform these things. I had to, like, do a diagnosis call it.
100xEngineers: whether, first of all, like, I'm talking to the right people, then, Understanding that
100xEngineers: What are the… what are the things, what are the workflows we can build?
100xEngineers: converting their evidence into the structured workflows, the triggers, the input, and steps. Now, why we are doing all of this is because, if you remember, the whole goal of this exercise
100xEngineers: is that I have an observation, which I saw that there are a lot of people who want to learn about AI, but they don't know exactly how to do it, or they can… they don't know how to build a proof of concept which can help them to get any kind of opportunity. So that's what we are doing, and this…
100xEngineers: is a manual MBV plan, so it goes through, like, each and everything, and the day 6 where it is mentioning, it's, it has mentioned that, it…
100xEngineers: Understands the particular problem in their day-to-day
100xEngineers: work, and it tries to, like, convert this into a structured map, right? Which… which basically, again, comes back to the same thing. The input, the steps, the decision points, the output, right? And I'll… I'll basically, like, zoom out here, and I'll just, like, take two things from this part as the input and output, and I'll connect these
100xEngineers: Same two things.
100xEngineers: here with our system design principle, right? The system which we are discussing.
100xEngineers: In my case, I need to make sure that I will teach Arav how to build
100xEngineers: a real impactful solution using AI, so that he doesn't feel overwhelmed, and he can actually, like, build a portfolio, which can help him to get the opportunity, right? Rather, a job opportunity, or maybe, like, him building his own business.
100xEngineers: So I have, like, first question to people who are following this.
100xEngineers: Especially for my problem statement context. What do you think? What's the… what's the input here?
100xEngineers: Let's define that.
100xEngineers: And this is how… how… activity…
100xEngineers: step will be, I would say.
100xEngineers: I'll actually define the input in this part.
100xEngineers: So I have, like, a whole system design ready. Because, as I said, I'll be building this section today.
100xEngineers: So I'll take this section right now, and I know my user.
100xEngineers: This is Arab.
100xEngineers: And you guys also need to have a clarity. Your user is…
100xEngineers: a person is not a target audience or a group, so always keep a user in your head, even if you have a group, like, pick one person from it when you're designing a system like this.
100xEngineers: Right now, I want to build an app which can run on a browser, so I'm not focusing on the native application. The reason why it's… it's easier and it's faster to run the iteration and build the MVPs here.
100xEngineers: But the question number one, as I said, like.
100xEngineers: if we have this problem statement, if RF is our user, what are the inputs we are expecting from the RF, and what is the output we should give?
100xEngineers: So, coming back to this, this is something where some of you might feel that it's too difficult to answer this question, but
100xEngineers: I'll just keep this hypothesis open.
100xEngineers: If you have your own hypothesis which is ready.
100xEngineers: You can use the MV plan, or you can use the hypothesis. I'll use the hypothesis right now, as it's, like, much more, easier, and I'll put this hypothesis…
100xEngineers: hair.
100xEngineers: If you have less than 21 days, can it still be done after discovery? Yes, we can do that, if you have achieved all the… all the outcomes which you're supposed to do.
100xEngineers: And, my voice is low.
100xEngineers: Let me check…
100xEngineers: Okay, now it's okay.
100xEngineers: It should be better now. Is it fine?
100xEngineers: Okay, awesome.
100xEngineers: Yes. So, what I was saying is, this is the hypothesis. I gave the case of RF. The first thing which we need to build our first interface and the system in this process is the input and output. Can you help me guess what is the right input and output we can decide for this particular example?
100xEngineers: After this, you guys can follow along and write the input and output for your problem statement.
100xEngineers: Just think about it, take a minute, maybe. You already have the document. If you don't have the document, I'll share the document once again with all of you. If you want to take a look at the MBP plan or any other part of it.
100xEngineers: Also, if you are building something for your own application, you can define the hypothesis, maybe you can share the discovery document, and you can mention the input-output for your problem statement as well. I would love to check it out.
100xEngineers: Although I'll be taking an example of my problem statement here, but that will… that will help you to take the next set of action after this.
100xEngineers: lecture.
100xEngineers: Omar, I'll… I'll talk to you after the lecture. I think this is not the right place for me to answer this. Maybe if you can, like, send me a DM, yeah, happy to check it out.
100xEngineers: Okay, Shafai said input is gonna be one specific scope workflow worth solving. Awesome. I love the answer, by the way.
100xEngineers: Anyone else has a… Has any idea about what could be the input?
100xEngineers: And also the output.
100xEngineers: Vijayita, input a problem statement.
100xEngineers: But again, I would say the problem statement
100xEngineers: is good, but it's a very vague input, don't you think, Vijaytha? Because problem statement can be anything.
100xEngineers: Like, I can tell that, hey, my washing machine is not working. That could be a problem statement.
100xEngineers: So, what I'm looking for is more specificity, and this is an exercise which is also gonna be really helpful for all of you to practice, like, every single time when you design
100xEngineers: user interfaces.
100xEngineers: So, Saluja said, context about the entire workflow, individual steps.
100xEngineers: Part of the workflow which is most painful, why the part is most painful.
100xEngineers: I like the specificity. Thank you so much, Saluja.
100xEngineers: Okay, Shefali has mentioned the output as well.
100xEngineers: Let me put the output here.
100xEngineers: So this is, Shapari's answer.
100xEngineers: I would, recommend, like, Vajitna to think about more specific one, but, here.
100xEngineers: The input is one specific scoped workflow, which is worth solving, and the output is identifying one real user, map one repeated workflow.
100xEngineers: build a working AI-assisted version and present a credible demo or a case study within 90 days, right? So, there are multiple inputs or outputs here, right? And that's something which…
100xEngineers: Which is exactly what I'm trying to understand, that…
100xEngineers: how will we pick the right input and output? But I like the answer, because it captures everything what you want to test.
100xEngineers: Harshit said, input is step…
100xEngineers: a user does to get to a certain point. Again, Hashid, I would force you to think about more specific answer than this one, because this is slightly more vague. And the reason why I'm coming back to this is, do you remember the last few weeks aside, I became a robot, and you guys were giving me instructions?
100xEngineers: That's basically what you are interacting with. Like, you guys will be working with machines, a browser. A browser doesn't understand what is a certain point you are…
100xEngineers: getting, or a user is trying to get to, right? A browser will only give you the website if you type the exact URL. It will not guess it.
100xEngineers: So, you have to just, like, think about the specific
100xEngineers: And being specific in the input and output. Because you're working with a deterministic system, not the AI system right now.
100xEngineers: you can, and you will be able to do it with AI when you only define it in raw input, but right now, we are building the system which can run on a browser, even if we don't have an AI. It should accept the input and give some relevant output back, which can solve a problem that we have decided that we want to solve it. In this case, I am taking the example of the RF problem statement.
100xEngineers: So I hope you get the point of the exercise. This is the live exercise which…
100xEngineers: Opens up your brain, because it forces you to think critically, as well as think about, like, the specificity of what exactly you need.
100xEngineers: Okay, Hunch has, the answer, I'll put that also on the board.
100xEngineers: This is what Hunch mentioned. Input is detailed process with a goal, thinking style, input and expected outputs, explain about all the edge cases, where things may break, and how to solve those. Output after analyzing, get a solution for repeatable patterns where all the variables
100xEngineers: in the process are fixed and defined. Again, the same thing, Hunch. I like the overall thought process behind it. It's a good input and output for a product manager and for a designer, but for an end user, we need to be more specific, like.
100xEngineers: Just think about, like, if some… if you are… if you have to, like, tell me the machine version of me, which is also, like, a real version of me,
100xEngineers: Like, a robot doesn't have any kind of AI, only can understand the instructions.
100xEngineers: So… How do you use this robot?
100xEngineers: Without an AI.
100xEngineers: to solve a problem of RF, right? So that is the…
100xEngineers: goal for us. Can we find the specific… can we articulate our inputs so specifically that even a dumb machine can understand what we want and give us the exact output that we are expecting?
100xEngineers: And I know for some people, it's gonna be difficult, because this is the problem statement that I gave you, right? And I have my own observation about it. But I think this is also one of the most, relatable examples, because I think, at least if you are not the same person who I'm describing the situation for, maybe you have at least, like, seen people around
100xEngineers: you in this community, right, who are facing this kind of problem. So, that's also, like, why I kept this problem as a common thing, which, basically, we're gonna be more relatable. But, yeah, I think that's the whole point of, like, doing this exercise.
100xEngineers: I hope now some of you start
100xEngineers: thinking about in the direction. I'll go to the latest chat answer, and I'll take last one, and then I'll try to give you about my thought process.
100xEngineers: How I would do it.
100xEngineers: Sanjeev said, Let me put this on my whiteboard, and then I'll… Read it out loud.
100xEngineers: The input is a designer explains their workflow, repeated tasks, creative goals, and design challenges. The output is a system identify repeatable patterns, create a faster AI-assisted design workflow. I love this answer, Sanjeev.
100xEngineers: This is exactly the kind of answer which I was looking for. Thank you so much for sharing this, by the way.
100xEngineers: And, although, unfortunately, I was not able to go through all the earlier examples, but I'll actually take this one, and I'll continue using it, because
100xEngineers: This is exactly what I was thinking of, right? When I think of… A problem statement like this.
100xEngineers: Where we had this hypothesis.
100xEngineers: of people who are AI-aware, but who have no shipped proof, and they are stuck because they lack a method to convert a broad AI possibility into one specific scoped workflow, which is word-solving. And if you provide a structured workflow diagnostic system, followed by a guided build sprint, then at least 60% of our active students will identify one real user map
100xEngineers: and one repeated workflow, and build a working AI-assisted version, present it, and present a credible demo or a case study within 90 days. That was our hypothesis. And I think, like, so far, everything which I saw, and this is what stood out, which is…
100xEngineers: We just…
100xEngineers: the reason why I tell you, like, it's a better way to start things, and I'm not saying this is the final input and output, but this is a really good starting point, because two things are there. One is the specificity, which I've been, like, trying to emphasize
100xEngineers: more.
100xEngineers: a designer explains their workflow, repeated tasks, creative goals, and design challenges. I can be slightly more specific here that I can exactly mention the which workflow, like, maybe taking the input, but I know that it's too much to type, so I still, like, consider this, like, something which is, like, genuine. But you can mention exactly, like, a specific workflow, repeated tasks, creative goals, and design challenges.
100xEngineers: could be an input. Let's say if Arab is a designer.
100xEngineers: maybe this could be a thing. Although in my story, Arav is a business analyst, so maybe it could look like something, whatever, like, a business analyst does, right? But this also works. And the output here is the system identifies the repeatable patterns and creates a faster AI-assisted design workflow.
100xEngineers: Now, this is something which RF can implement, and once it… he or she can implement this, then we have at least some sort of…
100xEngineers: roadmap which we can build around it, that, hey, I know that this is what I do, which is repeatable, and this is the thing which we can automate, and in the next 21 days, if I can, like, implement those things, then whenever I'm stuck, I can talk to somebody who is helping me to, like.
100xEngineers: I have to solve my doubts, I should be able to build, like, a solid proof of concept that can help me in my job, and I can present it, and I can share it as a case study with my team. And that actually is, like, solves, like, part of problem, not the entire one, but… and definitely worth
100xEngineers: testing it, right? This gives us a good testing ground as well. Now, I know, like, this is not a full solution. People have given me, like, more better solutions than this.
100xEngineers: Geek.
100xEngineers: But I would start with something more specific, and this is called the scoping.
100xEngineers: Right?
100xEngineers: Like, when you scope your problem statement down to something which is one specific task.
100xEngineers: So that you can build things around it, and you can test it around all of these things, and once you have tested it out, and once you've got the output, you can then move to the next part of it.
100xEngineers: So, coming back to the system which we need to build, now we got clarity on the input and output. I hope you also got clarity about the exercise which I was sharing. A quick recap of this exercise. What I wanted to show through this is that
100xEngineers: After doing the discovery.
100xEngineers: process that we have done, and we have got two documents, the discovery and the MVP plan.
100xEngineers: you run this MVP exercise, get the data.
100xEngineers: The actions and the outputs. And the first thing for us is to understand the input and output.
100xEngineers: What are the things?
100xEngineers: we… We need to take as the input.
100xEngineers: And you can write this sentence for your problem statement.
100xEngineers: For whatever problem you have taken for this discovery statement.
100xEngineers: just write down this thing where it takes XYZ as input, and returns, like, XYZ as an output in my case.
100xEngineers: As we have described, it takes…
100xEngineers: a workflow, a repeated task, or a creative goal as a… as an input, and it output repeatable patterns, with a faster AISS design workflow.
100xEngineers: Actually, I like the DJ partner's answer also, which I saw right now. It's actually slightly more specific.
100xEngineers: Yeah, but… You can see, like, now I hope, like, you guys are able to get to the…
100xEngineers: to the core of it, right? Just do the same exercise for your problem statement, and this is a step number one of, like, designing the better interfaces.
100xEngineers: Now, I have a question.
100xEngineers: Let's say you have designed the right input and output, and you have mapped it. All of you performed the exercise really well, you have performed the discovery.
100xEngineers: And… let's say, do a quick fast-forward.
100xEngineers: For the next 2-3 weeks.
100xEngineers: we learned how to build systems, and you guys built a system, a front-end system, that can take this input, and maybe also built a back-end system, like a whole thing, and gives the output back, which is the actual, let's say, a workflow, right, which solves the problem. Do you think our…
100xEngineers: task ends here, like, is that all we need?
100xEngineers: If not, what is missing here?
100xEngineers: Because I can… I can just pause my whiteboard, and I can…
100xEngineers: open, maybe, the code editor, I can start writing Python code, and I can start teaching you exactly, okay, take the input from the Python function, let's build a UI, and get the output back, and we can have, like, a front-end ready, and we'll finish a lecture in the next 10 to 15 minutes right now.
100xEngineers: But do you think that's gonna be enough?
100xEngineers: If you understand the input-output, if you build a front-end system which can take these input and give the output back, and even, let's say, assume you have built the backend system as well.
100xEngineers: Is it enough? If it is not enough, Then, what's missing here?
100xEngineers: Yes,
100xEngineers: A verifiability metric. Hansh mentioned this, Shayas mentioned this, Yasir has mentioned the validation. Yes, all of this, and all of you guys are correct.
100xEngineers: we lack some kind of, like, verification right now, because even if we build a faster AI accessory design workflow, or maybe, like, this build plan success metric, which is demo or case study ready.
100xEngineers: The only way we'll actually get the real output, and we should be able to create an impact.
100xEngineers: is if it is verified by somebody, like, maybe in this case, a real person in RF's team, who can look at this, that he has… he has created a workflow, or maybe a system that took an input, generated the output, and then it has given some kind of, like.
100xEngineers: impact, or maybe, provided some value to the business, or maybe to the team itself, right? And that always comes from a…
100xEngineers: particular metric, right? In this case, like, what is the metric we are trying to… to solve? And this is where I… I love the… the OPT framework comes very handy, so if you're not… if you're not using that, I would highly recommend you to check it out, but…
100xEngineers: I'll try to, like, do a just deep dive of this problem statement, and try to find a verification method here.
100xEngineers: One other thing for me here is… I'll… I'll be, like, really… precise.
100xEngineers: in this case, the input is correct. Like, somebody… in my case, I would, like,
100xEngineers: Because Arav is an analyst, so I'll just, like, mention.
100xEngineers: Explains their workflow repeat task.
100xEngineers: etc.
100xEngineers: I'll scope it down to… The task only. The workflow and the task.
100xEngineers: And the output is gonna be,
100xEngineers: what kind of system? So, I would basically say…
100xEngineers: For me, first, in order for me to verify, I need… Maybe a text.
100xEngineers: It's gonna be a text format, so I'm gonna, like, pick both of these things, and this is the second part of our exercise, is that once you have defined the input.
100xEngineers: and the output. We also need to know that this could be anything, right? So one thing which I corrected to…
100xEngineers: I think this was Sanjeev's answer, right? One thing, one correction to Sanjeev's answer here is that I made it slightly specific to Ara, and in the output, I have mentioned a written plan. So, what I have defined as well is the type.
100xEngineers: And I'm gonna define type is gonna be a text, because it can be any type.
100xEngineers: Output can be of a video, it could be a workflow, it could be a code file, it could be a…
100xEngineers: Like, an image file.
100xEngineers: So I need to be specific with the machine, because I know I'll be working with the machine, right? So, in both of my cases, I'll be using
100xEngineers: input type text and output type text. I'll take the input, which is gonna be an analyst explaining their workflow. This could also look like, and this is another great exercise, which I would tell all of you, because
100xEngineers: Did you see something which happened here on the whiteboard and in my brain as well? The moment I saw verification, I started changing things there, because I know that I cannot verify something which is vague.
100xEngineers: Like, if I just write, hey, this is… this system takes a problem statement, generates a workflow.
100xEngineers: And if I have to verify it, I can't do that, unless until I made everything very explicit, including the type of it, including the specific example. So, verification also, like, forces you to
100xEngineers: I would say increase the… the specificity in your answers, because otherwise, like, you can't write any… a good…
100xEngineers: Verification check.
100xEngineers: we've written the input, we've written the type of the input, and we've written the output. Now, I'll actually write, the… the example
100xEngineers: input, right? So, this is the description of it, like, what we will take.
100xEngineers: Now, for us, like, and this is…
100xEngineers: an exercise for all of you as well. Imagine the end user. In my case, my end user is Arav. I will be imagining that Arav's sitting in Pune.
100xEngineers: Doing his job.
100xEngineers: Looking at different tutorials.
100xEngineers: when Ara will use my application.
100xEngineers: What is the first thing you're gonna write?
100xEngineers: We have mentioned that you can take these kind of input.
100xEngineers: But what is the exact thing that Arab gonna type? And that is the same thing which you need to write here. Maybe you can assume or imagine your end user. In my case, I'll tell you…
100xEngineers: from what I can think of is… Because of our story,
100xEngineers: Arav can write that, hey, I…
100xEngineers: we can… we can build a system which can take the input, and we'll explain all of that. Let's say I'm explaining on a call that, hey, you need to tell me
100xEngineers: I need to explain your workflow, what you do on a day-to-day basis? And he'll say, hey, I… Open…
100xEngineers: My Vegeta. Vegeta is,
100xEngineers: task tracking software, by the way, like, people who don't know, but any kind of tracking software you can use, like Jira, you can use, any kind of, I would say, the tracking software.
100xEngineers: I'm assuming he's an analyst, so he must be using some kind of software which he used to track all the tasks.
100xEngineers: I opened Jira to check my… Weekly to-dos.
100xEngineers: Then… I'll… Check with…
100xEngineers: Then I'll check, the high… Priority task.
100xEngineers: I'll pick one…
100xEngineers: Create a report… And send it.
100xEngineers: to my managers, using… we, like, sent it to my manager on Slack.
100xEngineers: Or email.
100xEngineers: This is what…
100xEngineers: I can assume, like, RF's typing. And what… now I need to think about it, like, if this is the kind of input somebody can type, and it definitely needs a lot more empathy. For some people, it might seem that, hey, this guy is, like, spending time on something, which is, like, too easy, but…
100xEngineers: I would say this is one of the hardest jobs.
100xEngineers: When you design your software, because everything… after this, if you have figured out the right input, right output, the type, and the verification for it, which is also a part which we haven't added yet.
100xEngineers: everything becomes, like, just a specification. You can pass in as a prompt to any kind of whiteboarding software, and you can, like, build things from there. But the main part here is the thinking and the clarity of, the thinking about how this system operates.
100xEngineers: So, in my case, this is the example input. Now, I need to also think of
100xEngineers: Let's say if RF has written this input, what is the example output he will get?
100xEngineers: the actual output, for this example. He should be able to get, as we said, like, our system should produce a written plan. So it should be a plan, right? And this…
100xEngineers: I could think of, and I can imagine that this is a plan, it should tell step number one,
100xEngineers: maybe checking… So it identifies the repeatable parts.
100xEngineers: Repeatable patterns.
100xEngineers: checking JIRA, checking tasks, or maybe… I'll mention this here, and things like that. I'll basically not write everything, but I hope you got the point. The second thing is…
100xEngineers: it creates an AI-assisted design workflow. It also… in my case, like, it just, like, should give you the first, the repeatable task, and then tells you that
100xEngineers: What all things are.
100xEngineers: all things… Can be automated.
100xEngineers: And how?
100xEngineers: So that's… let's say the checking task can be automated, you can… it should be able to give you a plan that, in order for you to automate your Jira tickets, which you can check, or maybe writing an email, writing a Slack message, you need to perform XYZ steps. Because if you have a plan like this.
100xEngineers: Araf can check this out and execute the plan. And that's… that's the level of detailing what we need.
100xEngineers: In order for us to, like, now start putting up a verification check. Because now I can design a better verifiable metric. Because if…
100xEngineers: this is the output which I'm producing. I can tell what is a good output and what is a bad output for each and every example. And what I need to do is I need to build, in this case, my…
100xEngineers: Golden… Bears.
100xEngineers: Oof.
100xEngineers: Input and output.
100xEngineers: Now, what this golden pair means is that, just like what we have done, the example here.
100xEngineers: you will be writing a set of examples for your problem statement. What is the exact input your end user will type? Not you will type, but your end user will type, or you can expect them to type,
100xEngineers: And what is the output they will get? And what is the… this should be the ideal output. And once you have a golden pair.
100xEngineers: Everything, every decision which you take.
100xEngineers: is basically a downstream of all of this information, because now I can check, first of all.
100xEngineers: I'll build a verification or verifiable metric that
100xEngineers: whenever I build a system, and it generates the answer, how closer the answer it is to the… to my golden pair?
100xEngineers: if tomorrow I build this with using, let's say, an open source LLM, or maybe, like, a small language model.
100xEngineers: I know that that language model might hallucinate, or might give me, let's say, the answer which are not acceptable. So I need to have that kind of verification check, right? The method. So… and that verification check, I can only build if I know what is the idle input and idle output, which is what I'll get by writing, let's say, 5 or 10 examples like this.
100xEngineers: Now, for some of you, this still seemed like a lot of…
100xEngineers: planning and a lot of, like, theory and not writing software, but I would say this is exactly what the thought process goes behind writing software.
100xEngineers: every time I write software or I build any app, I don't start writing it directly open a code editor and start building it. I do the same exercise here, and I've been doing it for the last 9 years. And this is the same process which has helped me to
100xEngineers: get clarity on the exact specific requirements which I need to build, because then I can, like, eliminate everything else, and it becomes, like, much more easier for me to… to, like, move to the next step. So…
100xEngineers: coming… coming back to, now, actually executing these things, right? Like, I'll come back to the…
100xEngineers: Verification check right now.
100xEngineers: In this case, the verification would be, as I said, like,
100xEngineers: Keeping the golden pairs of input and output as…
100xEngineers: as the ideal goal, and checking against whether it is getting the answers which is closer to it or not. Now, some of you will ask me a question that, is it possible for us to, like, capture all the edge cases here? The answer is no, definitely, but it's a good starting point, and the more you start building it, the more you start testing it, that's the iteration. Nobody in this world has captured all the
100xEngineers: edge cases of the software that they are building. There will always be eBugs, there'll always be issues, but the goal here is to, like, start, like, doing this and at least give us a starting point, rather than just, like, overthinking about what all things can go wrong, but…
100xEngineers: This is a good enough information for us to start things right now.
100xEngineers: Now, I have a follow-up question for all of you. I hope this was easy enough to understand, whatever we have discussed so far.
100xEngineers: If this is the example input, and the output we want, this is the type of input and output.
100xEngineers: We have discussed about different interfaces.
100xEngineers: Right, the first thing which we need to build here is the user interface, even before building our front end.
100xEngineers: We need to build an interface.
100xEngineers: We have multiple options, and I'll give you some options right now.
100xEngineers: There's a whole study of, like, building these primitives from scratch, from cross-principles. Unfortunately, this is not a design cohort, but I would recommend you to actually, like, check more about it. I have written a guide, like, designed for non-designers, if you want to know more about the philosophy of it, like, the thinking process, and all those things.
100xEngineers: I can share the document, and I'll upload it on the LMS as well. So, go through that if somebody's, like, interested to do a deep dive into those things. In this case, because it's a part for me which we will be using to build interfaces, I will use the primitives rather than going into the first principle of designing a form and button from scratch.
100xEngineers: And I hope, like, that's something which we can all agree on the same page, that
100xEngineers: This is a more faster way of, like, doing it.
100xEngineers: Because, as I said, like, the goal here is to, like, learn how to apply AI and, to create the maximum impact, not to learn how to, like, design systems from scratch.
100xEngineers: So what I'll tell you right now is some interfaces which already exist in the market. Somebody has, like, thought about these interfaces and some design systems. Like, forms are one of them. Then I would say
100xEngineers: the chart.
100xEngineers: interface, which takes an input, just like ChartGPT. There's voice, there is video.
100xEngineers: as a video, you can think of, like, something like Zoom or Gmeet, what we have. Voice, I would…
100xEngineers: Pick, like, a voice call, a phone call.
100xEngineers: And, they're, like, multiple others.
100xEngineers: You can think of, like, different interfaces which already exist in the market. These are the things, how you interact with different softwares and different machines, right? I don't want to, like, make it, like, a whole buffet, so I'll keep it limited to, let's say, these.
100xEngineers: three options. And, I should not… I say four options. Forms, Chat, Voice, Video.
100xEngineers: Based on this data.
100xEngineers: What do you think which would be the ideal interface for us to start building this MVP?
100xEngineers: Now, the word here is DMV, which stands for Minimal Viable Product.
100xEngineers: So we don't need to, like, solve the entire problem, and that's why I said, like, we start step by step.
100xEngineers: But this is the list of interfaces we have.
100xEngineers: What do you think is gonna be the ideal interface? Or at least the starting one?
100xEngineers: Sorry, just to correct myself, the good starting point for us to, like, Solve it.
100xEngineers: Some people are saying forms, some people are saying charts.
100xEngineers: So I can't see any video and voice, which is great.
100xEngineers: You can do voice as well, by the way. You can do video call. As I said, like, all of these are, like, there's no right and wrong answer, to be honest here.
100xEngineers: Now, the right and wrong answer depends on the execution capability of who you are and who is building this NV, right? So, like, if I ask you from that lens.
100xEngineers: Let's say if you are building it today.
100xEngineers: What is the most convenient
100xEngineers: form of interface that you can build today, which can help you to validate this entire thing. Like, if you have a golden pair, this is the type of example input and output.
100xEngineers: Start with simplicity, yes.
100xEngineers: form chat.
100xEngineers: Yeah, I think it is gonna be slightly different for different people, but if it's form for you, then…
100xEngineers: That's great, like, and we have multiple interfaces already available for firm, by the way, so… We use something called Tally on 100X.
100xEngineers: Like, some people…
100xEngineers: like, make fun of this, that I'm teaching technology, I've been building software from the last 10 years, but when it comes to, like, our website, I don't know how many of you know about this, if I open the 100x Engineers website.
100xEngineers: All the forms are, like, for example, let's say this, this form, enrolling. There's a tally form, by the way, tally.so.
100xEngineers: It's… it's not, like, something which I have hard-coded.
100xEngineers: And do you know why? Because I realized after a point of time that what I need from my end user, like, if I'm, let's say.
100xEngineers: taking the information where, like, maybe I want to, like, do a masterclass on a topic, and I want to take this information, which is mostly their first name, last name, their phone number, email, and what's the role, so that we can, like, reach out to them if they… or they can reach out to us.
100xEngineers: If they find things helpful, and we can send them the recording, we can add them to a Zoom list, and they can attend the session.
100xEngineers: If I have to, like, do all of this thing.
100xEngineers: Forms become a good interface for me, and what I'm trying to do here is, like, I just need to find the most, I would say, reliable solution out there in the market. As of now, again, space objective opinion. I like Tally. You can use Google Forms as well, by the way. Google Forms… I used to use Google Forms a lot.
100xEngineers: Just recently, we shifted to…
100xEngineers: tell you, but if you are somebody who wants, or who is working with Google Forms, you can use that. This is a great other interface. Design different forms,
100xEngineers: And you can collect data from it.
100xEngineers: Solve the problem.
100xEngineers: Now, why I'm telling you all of this is because
100xEngineers: The more you see these kind of interfaces as a system, the less…
100xEngineers: overwhelming, first of all, it will get… it'll get for you, and it will become much more faster for you to test the ideas.
100xEngineers: Now, look at the entire problem statement once again. Maybe whatever problem statement you are solving, or if you don't have a problem statement, then you can look at this one.
100xEngineers: this was the hypothesis, right? And we discussed the process of getting the input and output.
100xEngineers: we came to a conclusion like this. This is the kind of input which we can expect from our users. This is the type, this is the example, maybe we'll write the five golden data set, and we can basically set the verification that these are the idle answers and idle output, and we can… we can basically
100xEngineers: start building it. And if we think that form is the right approach for this, we can end up, like, building a form, we can deploy it, we can start testing it right now, without wasting any time.
100xEngineers: And that's how we can basically move faster.
100xEngineers: And it also tells you a lot of evidence that maybe sometimes you don't need to write code, like, even for me, like, instead of, like, me writing code for each and everything, and then I have to maintain that code, I have to, like, do a lot of things, because I know I've been doing that. So, it's just easier for me to delegate, and if I can find a solution which does the job for me, which captures these inputs. Because a lot of the time, what happens is that
100xEngineers: we can still use this tally of Google Form.
100xEngineers: as the… You can say the front-end or the interface.
100xEngineers: Let me pick the tally one right now, as the interface, and then I can take this information, whatever Tally is sending me, and I can connect my own backend, right? This could be, like, designed by me, so now I focus more of my energy into building this part.
100xEngineers: Which is actually, like, something that I cannot…
100xEngineers: find the software from the, like, I would say, somewhere else. Right, so that… what this gives us sometimes is that
100xEngineers: Instead of focusing all of our time and energy into, like, just reinventing the wheels every single time, we can, like, if it is possible for you.
100xEngineers: you're solving a problem, and you have figured out that maybe a type of interface is helpful for you, and there's already a solution which can help you build a user interface for that. I gave you an example of, like, Form. You can take that, and you can, like, then take the information from there, because the main job here is to get the input.
100xEngineers: And then show the output back. Now, one thing which I'll argue in this problem statement is that people want the output immediately. With the form, output always depends on a human being, right?
100xEngineers: So, this is a major problem here. It works really well when you're doing a webinar. Like, when I'm doing a workshop, people don't want an immediate workshop response, in the sense, like, if somebody is filling the form.
100xEngineers: it's okay, even if I tell them that the workshop's gonna happen on Sunday, they'll wait until Sunday, right? It's not something which they are expecting. The… the thing they are expecting is the confirmation email that… whether the registration is confirmed or not. That I can send, right?
100xEngineers: But in this case, if Arab is writing all of this thing, out of… will not wait until Sunday.
100xEngineers: Or maybe, like, until whenever the person who is, like, looking at the form data write all of this plan and send the data back.
100xEngineers: we have already LMs with us, so in this case, like, the LMs can give the answer right there, and hopefully, like, we'll be able to
100xEngineers: It's a lot of problems. So, from that lens, I eliminate form as an option right now, because I don't think this is the best interface for me to have that
100xEngineers: interactive conversation. Because maybe, let's say, after getting this input.
100xEngineers: If I receive the output as a plan, and if I want to ask a follow-up question for this.
100xEngineers: keeping a state of all of this informed, and you should try this out, and that's why I'm saying this is a great exercise, that whatever interfaces you have, try to find a solution for it, and try to, like, play around with these solutions, and you'll get to learn a lot that
100xEngineers: how people have designed these interfaces, and for what kind of problems, or what kind of problems they solve really well. I know from my experience that, like, forms might not be the best interface when you need the interactive
100xEngineers: Communication going on between a user and the, like, system, or maybe, like, any other kind of different user, let's say.
100xEngineers: Now we have, like, these three things.
100xEngineers: chat, voice, video. All of these things can work well, but I will take a decision
100xEngineers: What is the easiest and most convenient for me?
100xEngineers: to deploy and to build right now, if I have to, like, test it out. And which points me to the next option, which is chat.
100xEngineers: And that's how I come to a conclusion that chat is going to be one of the type of interface, especially the user interface, which I will be using to solve this problem, because I know that input type is text, the output type is text, and I have
100xEngineers: tried forms, and forms won't work because it doesn't have the interactive element in it, and maybe, like, storing the information, having follow-ups, becomes very difficult to maintain over forms. So I would rather have a chat as an interface.
100xEngineers: Now, this gives us a very good starting point, that… This is our…
100xEngineers: one of the core decisions which we basically solved. First, the input and output, and second, the user interface.
100xEngineers: And I hope you got the thought process behind it, like…
100xEngineers: why we didn't go for it. But that could lead to infinite loop. I have tried that in agents.
100xEngineers: I'm not building an agent div, so…
100xEngineers: Yeah, I'm not building an agent, I'm just, like, trying to solve a problem.
100xEngineers: Maybe we'll use just, like, 11, we'll cap it, then.
100xEngineers: We can cap the number of follow-ups to maximum 3, and we can do that.
100xEngineers: This is what we got so far as… in terms of the clarity of
100xEngineers: The solution that we need to build.
100xEngineers: We need to take the input, and this is the input. The explanation of the workflow looks like this, and the output, which the system should care, and the interface is a chat. Now, this
100xEngineers: It's a good starting point for us to now start building things, and maybe, like, figuring out the options.
100xEngineers: again, as I said, like, you can take multiple options for you, which you can build using, like, no-code solutions or code solutions.
100xEngineers: for this track specifically, I'm gonna discuss the…
100xEngineers: code as an approach to build chat interfaces, right? One of the primary, like, focus for us, as I discussed, is gonna be, like.
100xEngineers: building these interfaces and entire the system with the code approach, but I hope now you also got some clarity that
100xEngineers: execution doesn't impact implementation a lot. It definitely gives you that quality, in the same way that how raw ingredients matter sometimes, but
100xEngineers: we have seen examples where franchises have scaled across the globe, with different countries, with different raw material and raw ingredients, as long as the process and the system remains the same. The McDonald's will be able to, like, put their recipe in India, Europe, in America.
100xEngineers: In all the countries, and they can still, like, have, if not the exact same taste, but, like, almost, like, similar taste.
100xEngineers: So that people can, like, still, like.
100xEngineers: willing to have the bubble there, right? Irrespective of whatever they are… the raw material they are using. In the same way, the problem that you are solving, the raw materials here can change, like, somewhere, maybe a partner of you can… who is basically right now attending Abhisheikh's lecture, they'll use the no-code tools to build a chat interface, but we can use a code as one of the ingredients.
100xEngineers: to implement this.
100xEngineers: In this…
100xEngineers: code approach, as I said, the thing which I clarified in the beginning is the Python, the workflow we should be using and building everything on Python. There are multiple different approaches with code.
100xEngineers: So I'm trying to, like, reduce the number of decisions for you guys. You don't need to think about it. There are HTML, CSS, JavaScript, there are C, C++, XYZ languages. I'll help you to pick one, which is Python.
100xEngineers: In Python, there are, like, multiple ways to build chat apps.
100xEngineers: One is you can write the whole code by yourself. By default, Python doesn't have the ability to build browser apps. It started as a scripting language, which used to write scripts
100xEngineers: Later on became, like, an object-oriented programming language, which people started using it to do much more complex stuff than just writing scripts.
100xEngineers: One of the ways how we're gonna build a browser-based application, especially the chat application with Python, is by using an implementation of Python that allows us to build web application, and this is called Gradio. So I've done this research already for you, and
100xEngineers: In this case, I'm… I'm not going, like, asking people that, okay, what is the right approach and what is the wrong approach? I'm trying to give you a more…
100xEngineers: Like, deterministic answers, because This reduces… the…
100xEngineers: The amount of decisions we need to take. And we can scope everything down to, like, one framework.
100xEngineers: This is the level one. If somebody wants to start, Building user interfaces.
100xEngineers: You have not written code in your life.
100xEngineers: And you are solving a problem to build chat interfaces, or maybe any kind of interfaces, in general.
100xEngineers: with a code approach, I would first help you to decide that Python is going to be the easiest language for you to learn, for majority of the audience, unless until you have already learned something. And then, Gradio's gonna be the… because I've tried a lot of other implementations, it's gonna be the easiest implementation for you to build a simple chat app.
100xEngineers: I'll share level 2 resources in the next lectures and in the upcoming lectures. I'll have a full recorded series for this, but today I'm going to talk about radio as an example.
100xEngineers: Let's learn quickly about Gradio. So, I'll share this document with all of you, and this is…
100xEngineers: the Gradio.app. What I want right now to all of you to do is…
100xEngineers: radio.app. Just go to this website.
100xEngineers: Python is not eco-Subacin. Python is a language.
100xEngineers: Just like English is a language, and we can use English to communicate anything, we can use it to, like, influence people, to create content, to teach people, so that's… that's a analogy, if I have to, like, give you, Nickel.
100xEngineers: No, Gradio and Streamlit are different applications. So, Streamlit is a level 2 for me, and I'll share the
100xEngineers: streamlined resources in the LMS, but right now I'll focus on Gradio first, but these are two different frameworks.
100xEngineers: Everybody on the radio website?
100xEngineers: So, first thing which I want you to do is, you can… Scroll down… to this section.
100xEngineers: I want everybody to scroll down to this section, just, maybe you can open on your browser. You don't need to download anything, you don't need to install anything, just need to go to gradu.app, and scroll to this section.
100xEngineers: I'll zoom it here, and this is the Python code.
100xEngineers: Which you need to write in order for you to build a simple interface that can take an input and give an output. So here, this is the form input, by the way. So it's kind of the form interface.
100xEngineers: Not the chat one. The form interface usually has an input field. In this case, it's the text type field, so I can write my name.
100xEngineers: And the output here… If I submit, so it's gonna give me Hello Siddhanth, which is very basic output.
100xEngineers: And the buttons which are written here, if I click on the clear, it'll clear everything. If I click on submit, it will submit this, and hopefully, this time, if I click SID, submit, it'll give me the name HelloSet. So what is happening right now is, with Python, we have
100xEngineers: return these four lines of code. First thing, we need to import Gradio, and what is Gradio?
100xEngineers: This is the whole application. So, Gradio lets you build applications in Python.
100xEngineers: helps you to create web interfaces for your… this was… this was one of the projects which was initially got popular among
100xEngineers: ML engineers and, research communities, because most of these researchers used to work heavily with Python, but they were not, like, engineers who can, like, build a sophisticated UI and UX. So, this started as, like, a project to basically help those people, but over time, it… it got…
100xEngineers: very serious popularity, so it's right now sitting at somewhere around 42,000 stars, open source project, Hugging Face, acquired this company, by the way, and the…
100xEngineers: right now, this is for all elements, right? I was talking about interfaces, these are the primitives of those interfaces, like the buttons, the files, the options, all of these things. So whatever interfaces, you can build otherwise.
100xEngineers: in any other design software, or maybe on code software as well. You can find all of these components here, and you can
100xEngineers: play around with these components, and you can build any kind of UI. One of the easiest examples what Credio has given us here, is that
100xEngineers: because it's a Python library, which means it's… somebody has written a set of code already for you, and you need to, like, import Gradio. This is the line number 1, which is a standard command in Python to import any kind of library. So you mentioned the library name,
100xEngineers: And this is the function. I'm not gonna, again, explain the details of Python, because this is what I assume. If you've already gone through the big binary exercises, you know how to write a simple function. This is the keyword in Python, which tells you that this is the function, and the name of the function. This part is the input to the function.
100xEngineers: then this NEME is the input to the function, and then whatever you want to write after the return statement is gonna become the output. So in this case, this is the output, which is the hello plus name, plus the exclamation mark. Input and output.
100xEngineers: That's how the entire programming works. So I was telling you, if I can compress the information of all the engineering in just, like, one diagram, the diagram is still valid. The goal is to always identify the input and build a subsystem of those
100xEngineers: small functions, small programs which can take an input and give the output back. And the entire job of us as builders is to figure out, like, how do we convert these inputs into output by building more smaller systems around it.
100xEngineers: In this case, the system is doing nothing, it's just, like, adding hello and exclamation mark. And, the third line here is.
100xEngineers: GR.interface. So here, they're literally using the interface as a keyword, although it's a metaphor here, like, for me, but it's a keyword as well. So, Gradio has multiple interfaces.
100xEngineers: And you can choose and pick, just like what I was giving you option here.
100xEngineers: like, you have multiple interfaces, options, like poems, chat, voice, and you can build your own custom interface as well, right, if you want to go deep. That's, again, not the realm which I'm gonna cover in this cohort, but if you… if you are somebody who is curious, I'm happy to share more resources on this.
100xEngineers: In this part, like, we can pick a specific type of interface, which takes the input.
100xEngineers: as a text format. Now, this is exactly where every principle which we have discussed on the whiteboard's gonna map into the codebase. That's why I said the thing which we have done here is not theory, this is the thinking part, this is the
100xEngineers: architecture setting of what we're doing, right? So we designed already the input, which is gonna be text type, output gonna be a text type, the interface gonna be a chat type.
100xEngineers: In this case, radio gives us
100xEngineers: option to choose different interfaces. Right now, it's like a simple text-based interface, which takes the input in a text field, gives the output in a text field, and it connects it to a function. So this FN stands for a function. So whatever name of the function you want to write here.
100xEngineers: And wherever in this file this function is written, Python will find this function, and will execute this function with the
100xEngineers: exact inputs, what you will write in this field. In this case, the SID will become the input.
100xEngineers: If I upload an image, it won't accept it, because this interface only accepts
100xEngineers: text, and then it will take this input, which is said.
100xEngineers: from this interface, send it to this greet function. Now, this greet function
100xEngineers: Takes a name as an input, and add these things.
100xEngineers: and returns it. And when it returns it, it gives the output in the text format, which is…
100xEngineers: Exactly here. So this is a block which is already pre-designed by Credio, and what you need to do is just to
100xEngineers: mention the right input or output, and the type, which is what we have done here. And the last line is demo.launch, which is whatever interface you build, this is how Python variable works. You create a variable for it, so that,
100xEngineers: Like, you can use the same interface function to create multiple interfaces, and you can store that interface in this variable. And the moment you use the launch function, it will launch the application, and that's how you see everything, whatever is there.
100xEngineers: Very simple, but the most powerful
100xEngineers: application of each and everything what we have seen. Because once you understand how things map here in the code.
100xEngineers: You don't wipe code, and that's my recommendation for the next one week.
100xEngineers: If you want to learn, don't use AI to write this code, because it hardly gonna take you less
100xEngineers: time to write these four lines, as compared to you writing a prompt, and then copy-pasting that prompt, and then testing it. And the goal here is to understand these things.
100xEngineers: like, from first principles, so that tomorrow, once you know that this is the input, this is the interface, and this is the type, and if tomorrow AI makes a mistake, and something goes wrong, you can debug those things.
100xEngineers: This is what we discussed about one type of interface.
100xEngineers: I'm gonna go to the chat. This is what we have. We have, by the way, like, all…
100xEngineers: other type of interfaces as well, the diffusion phases. Somebody who has built a…
100xEngineers: Diffusion workflow, I would highly recommend you to check this out. If you're building any map-based workflows, you can check out the map interfaces. And there's a whole library, if you want to go, into the details of it. This is the custom component library, and they have, like, a whole docs, which you can,
100xEngineers: Which you can check out. Let me see if I can…
100xEngineers: yeah, get started on this. So, there's, like, a lot of, like, different features, like this, the custom components, which are here already.
100xEngineers: I'll share all of this information, but I don't want to distract you guys from the main…
100xEngineers: agenda, which was… To build a chat interface.
100xEngineers: This is the one which I'll be focusing on. And as you can see right now, this…
100xEngineers: Is the interface which we get as a chat.
100xEngineers: And if I can type anything, let's say if I type here, I'll right now get the same message, which is e-code back, and I also have, like, a small history of all the messages which I have typed here.
100xEngineers: So it's a pretty decent interface already, which is gonna be helpful for me to, like, have a conversation, and now I can see how my…
100xEngineers: Input and output, which we discussed.
100xEngineers: I'm gonna map into this, where we take…
100xEngineers: an input like this. Let me copy this entire part.
100xEngineers: And if I go here… I can type this thing, and I can behave like…
100xEngineers: Out of right now, but…
100xEngineers: I'm assuming this is what Arav will see, and here he will type, okay, this is what I'm facing as a problem, and instead of now
100xEngineers: like, getting the same answer back, we will build a system that will give the plan back to the RF, right? But from the interface lens, the way the interaction works, I am pretty happy, because this is exactly the kind of interaction which I wanted for my problem statement, which is more interactive than a form.
100xEngineers: Right? And although, like, someone can argue that maybe we could build something like this, the Hello World example, yes, you can do that, by the way. Like, so there is… again, I said.
100xEngineers: No right and wrong answer.
100xEngineers: Somebody could also build a video solution for it, somebody could build a voice solution for it.
100xEngineers: it's my personal joy, and that's where the design differs, right? Somebody can design the same software
100xEngineers: with a different interface, and still win the market, and someone will have, like, a completely different interface, and they can have, like, a different audience to it. So, there's no right and wrong answer, it's just the answer which appeals to me at this moment, and which solves the problem of my end user.
100xEngineers: So I picked the interface here, and now, for me, it's how I can Start.
100xEngineers: putting things down, and also, like, deploy it. For all of you, I'll give you the next set of exercise, and this is something which you guys can follow along.
100xEngineers: We have to do it.
100xEngineers: on Hugging Face spaces. So, if you are somebody who's new to Hugging Face.
100xEngineers: I would recommend you to log into this application.
100xEngineers: Dave Sharma, I will come to everything, whatever you're saying, but I think… let's just forget for a moment that we know everything, what you… what you know already. I'll come back to MCP, everything. We're trying to, like.
100xEngineers: go through a journey, right? Just imagine this series of lecture is…
100xEngineers: It's a journey where you have, like, You're observing, you're learning things.
100xEngineers: from first principles. I know there are things that exist in the market, it's a better way to do all of these things, but the point here is not to, like, find the most optimized solution and, like, to build the most scalable thing right now is to learn how to think from first principles and design a system, so we learn those skills of designing these, or building these systems, taking the input and output. So in future, if you have to debug things, if you have to, like, go down.
100xEngineers: We have their vocabulary and we have the understanding to it. So, I'll come back to all the answers, but that's a good way to, like, look at these lectures.
100xEngineers: Rather than thinking that.
100xEngineers: we already have solutions why we are spending time on doing this, because then it won't make sense to you, like, whatever I'm trying to say. But, coming back to it, the exercise which I want to do right now is…
100xEngineers: We have identified a very big part of, by the way, our journey, which is understanding the input-output, the first part, the user interface, we have defined a chart, we're gonna use the Python for it, and we're gonna build everything using the Gradio, the first interface. We also identified the exact interface which is available on the Gradio's website as a component which exists, and we have tested this interface. Right now, it takes the input, gives the output back.
100xEngineers: Now, the goal for us to actually build and deploy it for us, and we're gonna use this for the next two weeks, where we can, like, finish our entire application. The way to do that is first go to this website called huggingphase.co slash spaces. Huggingphase.com is a company. Spaces is the product. So if you have gone to this website, let me know in the chat. You can raise your hand. I want to keep a track of how many people are following it.
100xEngineers: Because if you're not following it, you can still watch me, but you won't get the, as I said, like, maximum value out of it. How many of you are on this website? You have logged into Hugging Face?
100xEngineers: Quick raise of hands.
100xEngineers: Awesome, that's great, Sanjeeb, if you're already following it. So, if you're on Spaces, the first thing which I want you to do is…
100xEngineers: Go to this, profile section.
100xEngineers: And click on New Space.
100xEngineers: Go to the profile section and click on New Space.
100xEngineers: When you click on New Space, this is the form you should be able to see, and give a name to your space.
100xEngineers: I will write…
100xEngineers: Actually, the chat… C7.
100xEngineers: I'm not adding description. If you want, you can add it. I'm not changing anything else. I'll keep the Gradio default selected. It is selected, so I'll just let it be.
100xEngineers: I'll keep the blank.
100xEngineers: selected already, although I have some templates already, but…
100xEngineers: I'll, I'll start everything from fresh, fresh.
100xEngineers: Won't change anything, space hardware, I'll keep the free one.
100xEngineers: This is a hardware where your code's gonna be running.
100xEngineers: All of these things, I'll keep it default.
100xEngineers: this can be publicly accessible, so right now I know that I won't add any sensitive information. But tomorrow, if I want to make it private, I can do that. As of now, I won't need anything, I just, like, mention the name for the space. So that's what I expect you guys to do as well, to follow along. Just go to Hugging Face Spaces.
100xEngineers: Click on your profile icon.
100xEngineers: New space, write the space name, and then scroll down.
100xEngineers: Click on Create Space.
100xEngineers: Once you click on this Create Space, this is the screen, ideally, you should… you should see.
100xEngineers: A lot of things here.
100xEngineers: there are multiple ways to do this. I will first teach you the most simplest way, then we'll go, as I said, like, level 2 and level 3 of, like, doing it from that. The most simplest version to add anything to Hugging Face Spaces dashboard from the web app
100xEngineers: is by using their web UI, and you can click on this There is the shortcut.
100xEngineers: You can create the app.py file directly in your browser.
100xEngineers: So, this is not, like, a button, but it's a hyperlink.
100xEngineers: Just to zoom in, this is the link you need to click on. If you click on this link.
100xEngineers: It will lead you to this application.
100xEngineers: Now, this is a blank app, and this is where exactly you will be writing your Gradio code.
100xEngineers: So, what I need is radio code right now, and I'll go back. First, I will test with the basic interface.
100xEngineers: I'll copy everything, because I can see the code, I can see the output, I know it's working.
100xEngineers: I'll copy all these… Four lines of code.
100xEngineers: And I'll go back to my Hugging Face… Hugging Face space.
100xEngineers: I'll paste it exactly in this… File, this is the… Edit file.
100xEngineers: And then I commit… click on this commit new file domain.
100xEngineers: when I do it, I can see this…
100xEngineers: Can… this has created a new file app.py, and it has started something.
100xEngineers: What it has started is the build process.
100xEngineers: And if I switch to the app tab, so I was on the files tab by default when I create a file, but if I switch to this app tab.
100xEngineers: I can see the application is starting up, so this is what is happening.
100xEngineers: Hugging Face.
100xEngineers: is giving you a free hardware where you can run your Python code, specifically the Gradio, because they've already installed it, and
100xEngineers: Immediately, right now, everything is running, it's running on Lambda. We have our first Python app deployed, up and running successfully. Let me know how many of you have reached to this position, or to this place, where you have
100xEngineers: took your first code from the Gradio, put it into Hugging Face Spaces, created a new space, and deployed it, and you can see something like this.
100xEngineers: It's okay, it'll take some time for some people.
100xEngineers: Awesome. Nikhil is done. Nikhil, can you share your screenshot? Actually, you can also do something better than screenshot. You can click on these three dots, and you can click on this embed this space.
100xEngineers: When you go to this embed space, you will find a direct URL. And you can copy this direct URL, and you can share this URL with everybody. So right now, all of you will have access to the app that I just created live on this call.
100xEngineers: And you guys can also share the URL of your application.
100xEngineers: You can make some changes to this application so that
100xEngineers: it also becomes a part of you. And how to make changes is go to the Files tab once again, and go to the app.py, and here, in this logic.
100xEngineers: Let me click on the edit file, so you can edit your files from here itself. In this edit file, instead of saying hello, you can say.
100xEngineers: Hello?
100xEngineers: I'll write… Analytics…
100xEngineers: engineer, and then I'll write name. So that way, like, I know if you are using my application.
100xEngineers: it will give you the answer, Hello 100x engineer, plus your name. That's the only change which I'm doing. Just make sure that you won't break any other code, because this is a text string, so if you're writing something, I would recommend you to make your first change like this. It's gonna be something which you can add, maybe, which signifies that it's
100xEngineers: It's gonna give you the output which is for you. So, now it will start again, hopefully.
100xEngineers: And, let me test.
100xEngineers: If this is…
100xEngineers: Okay, so right now it's working. Sid, hello 100X engineer, Sid, there's a problem that the space is not considered, but, I'm fine with that. I don't want to make changes right now, but I can add one more space.
100xEngineers: Here's something which I've built, and I can share this…
100xEngineers: Space link with all of you, and you can check this out.
100xEngineers: I would love to see some of your examples.
100xEngineers: And also, just… can somebody… or can you guys, like, lower your hand raise, people who have raised previously, and just raise your hand if you have completed this step, if you have…
100xEngineers: Built your first radio application, and deployed it on Hugging Face Spaces.
100xEngineers: Awesome, we have more than 7 people, 8 people, actually 10 people. Wow, number is going up.
100xEngineers: First of all, congratulations to all of you guys.
100xEngineers: You know, this is what took me first 3 months of my life when I was, like, learning engineering.
100xEngineers: to just put something out there which is live, accessible to the entire world, and I can interact with it. And you guys have learned it in just, like, 5 minutes. Without using AI. That's the best part.
100xEngineers: Hello world, this is the Hello World equivalent in the Gradio app. Yes, Dave.
100xEngineers: But, awesome. First of all, this is great.
100xEngineers: I think, yeah, I'll come back to you, maybe, like, I know I can't do the debugging, but what I would recommend is maybe anyone who is facing a problem, you can take a screenshot of it and post it on the Discord, so right after this, someone from our team will reply back on that.
100xEngineers: But hopefully, like, this should be easy, because it's a very straightforward part, and even if you are somebody who's facing the problem, after this call, I'll go through the solutions, or the fixes, I'll send you the solution.
100xEngineers: How do I stop this application? Right now.
100xEngineers: This application runs on a free hardware, so you don't need to…
100xEngineers: like, stop it as of now. It uses a concept of, like, cold start, which means that if the app is running,
100xEngineers: the Hugging Face space will allocate a server to it. If the app is not running, it will automatically, like, shut it down. And next time, whenever you're using the app, then it'll take, like, I would say a couple of seconds, sometimes a minute, to run this application. So you don't have to manage
100xEngineers: in a way, how you manage a Jarvis Labs, it's just completely free of cost.
100xEngineers: That way, it's also, like, one of the best resources right now for me when I'm teaching, because you guys can, like, without
100xEngineers: doing a whole setup on your machine, you can still have, the code which you can deploy and which you can share with everybody. But coming back to it, like, this is something which…
100xEngineers: is a great Hello World program, as what they've shared, but we want to do something more, right? We want to build a full-blown chat application, which can not only take
100xEngineers: the raw input, but can also solve the problem of RF, because that's what we are doing in this, right? We're not, like, here for fancy or, like, good-looking demos.
100xEngineers: Now, coming back to it.
100xEngineers: I'll go to the chatbot part, and I'll…
100xEngineers: I'll try to, like, find this on…
100xEngineers: Spaces already. By the way, this already… this already exists on spaces.
100xEngineers: In order for me to make changes, what I can do is…
100xEngineers: I can go to the… the file here, and I'll… Copy all of this.
100xEngineers: And I'll go back to my file.
100xEngineers: I'll replace app.py, I click on the edit file, I'll delete everything.
100xEngineers: And I'll paste this part.
100xEngineers: And I'll click on Commit Changes to Main.
100xEngineers: It'll again start. Right now, it's building.
100xEngineers: So once the status of building is done, it… it should be able to, like, show me the application. So right now, it's restarting the space.
100xEngineers: Now, what this does, and I'll… meanwhile, when it is restarting, I'll try to explain you the codebase. I hope you got…
100xEngineers: The last code which we… which we just deployed, this was on… the Hello World program.
100xEngineers: Where we had the interface, I was telling you, which is the…
100xEngineers: Input text type, and output the text type takes a field, kind of a form, like a mini form, with only one field and one output field.
100xEngineers: What we are doing with chart application, we're changing the interface first, and then we're changing the function.
100xEngineers: So, we…
100xEngineers: we have a chat interface already, so if you see, like, by default, the interface, what Gradio uses, is the form interface, the text input field, right? If you want to use a specific interface, you can use chat interface. How many interfaces are like that? There.
100xEngineers: you can go to the guide, the Get Started Guide section, and you can find all the examples here.
100xEngineers: So, you have the chatbot interfaces, you have the streaming interfaces, these are the custom components, and there are, like… if I go down here, I think…
100xEngineers: Yeah, this is the interface class in itself, which tells you, like, all the interfaces which are available, and how the Gradio is built. If you're somebody who's a developer, I would recommend you to, like, check this out.
100xEngineers: Although, I would not want you to really check out everything, because there are a lot of things here on this website. I'll give you, like, a specific suggestion of few tutorials from this, specifically to build the chat app, which is much more focused towards what we are building.
100xEngineers: Let me share the link. So this is the how to create a chatbot example. This is the guide which I'll share with all of you. Right now, I'll share it.
100xEngineers: So that you guys can, check it out.
100xEngineers: But this is a quick homework, and it'll teach you exactly how to plug this chat interface, step-by-step approach.
100xEngineers: Whether this is a… this is the only line, if you are somebody who is, like, starting from scratch, this is the only line which you need to write in order for you to have an output like this.
100xEngineers: Which is a chat interface. However, what output we got is slightly more complicated, because it has multiple elements. It has, like, one sidebar, it has, like, a function which responds exactly something
100xEngineers: And it writes some messages. So, it has ex… in this tutorial, it has explained line by line that… how you can connect this chat interface with the… with the function, and, like, how you can build a same chatbot which we have here. I will…
100xEngineers: Just mention here that this is the interface, the gradient.Chat interface we are using.
100xEngineers: And, one thing which…
100xEngineers: we are… we are taking… taking out here is we want to, like, save the history, so that we can see the conversation. So this is a flag which already interface… the chat interface gives us.
100xEngineers: There are some options which are already available, like the likes, spam, inappropriate, others. These are all the options which are available, which are built by the radio, so I can, like, use all of this.
100xEngineers: One thing which I want to, like, connect with chat interface, so this is a function which we have used, and as I mentioned it here.
100xEngineers: This is how you can use a chart interface on a very basic level. Just, you write gr.chartinterface, you mention your function name.launch, it'll launch the interface.
100xEngineers: So it needs, like, minimum one function, and then all other inputs are optional, not required, in this case, what we have given. But this function is the mandatory function, because it connects this chat interface
100xEngineers: with a function that can execute something. It can take the input and can take the output. By default, the chat interface function takes two input, messages and the history, which is the history of the messages. And, what we are doing here, again, I'm not going detailed into the programming, because this is what I expect to have done in the Python bootcamp.
100xEngineers: On Big Binary. This is a for loop. A for loop… Basically, goes from…
100xEngineers: A point to the maximum length of a message that you receive, and then it Send you the output.
100xEngineers: step by step. So this is what the slow eco does, which is basically, instead of, like, doing the eco exactly, it simulates the streaming token behavior of what LLM does.
100xEngineers: And, that's what, basically, it is doing. So it's giving you the output one by one, based on how many, characters are there for the messages. So it looks like that something is getting streamed. So it's just, like, giving us that feel. Now, everything is, by the way,
100xEngineers: deployed on the same app container, so the app which we have seen. Now I can type the message here.
100xEngineers: And, I should be able to see that, okay, I… although this time it was a small message, but if I go back and mention the same one, I should be able to see the streaming happening in front of me.
100xEngineers: So…
100xEngineers: So now my interface is up and running. In the same manner, I can share this embed… I can embed this as an iframe in any website. I can add this in my, script as well. If I just want to directly use it as an app, I can share this other URL. So you guys can all check this out as well.
100xEngineers: Can't find the source code for the chatbot. Someone help.
100xEngineers: I'll share that. I have already shared, by the way, one of mine, so you can just use this one, and you can go to the file section.
100xEngineers: And then you can click on app.py. This is where you will find the chat code.
100xEngineers: Now, with this, we have something which is useful. It's not, like, something which is fancy or, but which is also not very useless. I can actually…
100xEngineers: now apply everything what we have discussed, and I have, like, a… my first interface, which is up and running.
100xEngineers: First of all, kudos to all of you guys who were able to follow along with this, because this is what we've been discussing, like, last week, right? And I think to make a jump like that, where
100xEngineers: you being a user to somebody who can now, like, start building the interfaces that can interact, and you can also deploy and share this with the world, which is, like, now setting or having a server. Anyone from the world can…
100xEngineers: like, interact with this application, and you can make changes to it. You can, like, start, like, understanding it. So your Python knowledge and your system design knowledge is now…
100xEngineers: getting combined here. One of the excites which I will give you after this is that
100xEngineers: go through this tutorial, how to create a chatbot with Gradio, read this tutorial line by line.
100xEngineers: Install Python locally on your machine.
100xEngineers: For this session, I did everything on the cloud version of the Hugging Face Spaces, and you can follow along for that, but I don't want you to do that, because
100xEngineers: Over time, when you have a full-blown, full, I would say, blown application in front of you, which has the backend, front-end LLMs, data storage, it might have some, some keys, you might need to, like,
100xEngineers: keep a history of all of these things, and it just becomes a bigger project. So, it's easier for you to, like, look at that project and, like, think about it in local editor. One of the editors which I would recommend right now, which I also use, is Cursor, so you can use
100xEngineers: So this is a recommendation, not, I would say, a requirement or a mandatory restriction. If you are somebody who is using VS Code, something like that, if you're already a developer, you can continue using that as well.
100xEngineers: But if you are not using anything, and this is the first time you are writing code, or you are using… you want to use code on your machine.
100xEngineers: then I would recommend Cursor. You can use a free version of it, it has a generous free plan.
100xEngineers: Which, like, at least helps you to, like, guide
100xEngineers: what you want to build, and I use this approach a lot, where I open cursor, so just to showcase how the cursor looks like when you open on your machine.
100xEngineers: After downloading it.
100xEngineers: It, it gives you…
100xEngineers: It can… it gives you this kind of interface. Let me open this.
100xEngineers: And let's say this is where your, like, Python code is running, and let's say you just, like, copy-pasted something from…
100xEngineers: what we have been building, and now you want to do it locally on your machine. So…
100xEngineers: the reason why I like cursor more, as compared to others, is, first of all, the Composer model is, like, really good. If you are using…
100xEngineers: like, the cursor default mode. It uses the composer model, which is effective, for, like, coding and even in general, learning. I find it, like, for beginners, it's, like, much easier, because you don't need to buy multiple subscriptions. You can also, like, use a lot more things on their free plan right now.
100xEngineers: Let's say you have this Gradio code, right, which you have built.
100xEngineers: Thanks, man.
100xEngineers: I'll copy this part.
100xEngineers: And I'll paste it here. So this is my Gradio code.
100xEngineers: The way how you build or you create a new file is you can… either you can do a Command-N if you're on Mac, or you can click on this new file function, and you can write a name of your file, yourapp.py, and then you can, like, paste things here. So that becomes a way to…
100xEngineers: Like, create and add new files.
100xEngineers: And then, if you want to explain anything.
100xEngineers: let's say I want to understand what this function is doing, or what this particular line is doing. I can click on Add to Chat, and I can ask it to explain
100xEngineers: What this is doing.
100xEngineers: And while it is good for me to learn things about, like, what the explanation is, I would recommend you to not use cursor to, like, write everything down, or maybe, like, build everything, because then you won't be able to, like.
100xEngineers: learn the fundamentals of it. So, just make sure, like, use it to…
100xEngineers: To understand, like, what's going on with the code, rather than just writing instructions and, like, telling it, like, whatever.
100xEngineers: you want to build. I think it'll take some time. Let me see if… if I have done the… yeah, that's the auto only.
100xEngineers: So, this is one of the prerequisite requirements from the next lecture onwards. Download the cursor locally. Make sure you have Python as well. So, the second thing which you might need, is Python installation, if you're on Windows. So, I'll share you the file, a step-by-step file, which will help you to, like.
100xEngineers: And go through all the steps.
100xEngineers: like, how do you download, but it's pretty straightforward, not very difficult. You can… based on your operating system, you can download the Python. There are, like, multiple tutorials out there, but I'll still upload one file. Download a tutorial, download the Python, sorry. Watch this tutorial, like, follow this along,
100xEngineers: download occurs. These are the three things which I need you to do before you start your next office hour or next lecture.
100xEngineers: And that will help you to, like, set up a good foundation for your local model. Now, what I want to, like, end this lecture on is basically
100xEngineers: On a quick exercise that, along with whatever we have done today, what is about defining the input from our discovery document, the type and the output, and then also defining the interface, and then picking one interface.
100xEngineers: from the Gradio, because I've selected the Gradio library, so going to the Gradio app and understanding what kind of interfaces are. I would force all of you to, like, think about the chat first.
100xEngineers: Right now, so that…
100xEngineers: at least you can build a chat version of whatever application you are building. And some of you might not be fully convinced for this as an idea that some of you might be actually solving a problem which cannot be exactly, like, you can say, built using a chat interface, and which might require something more complicated, which is completely fine. I would just try to, like, suggest you to look… find, like, at least one part of the application, so that you can complete this first
100xEngineers: exercise as a practice set, and you get familiar with the platform. So the goal here is to also get
100xEngineers: familiarity, rather than, like, building the perfect output. And once you do that, then you can
100xEngineers: go and pick different options from Gradio, because Gradio has, like, plenty of options. You can build a Discord bot app, you can build a Slack bot, you can build a website widget, you can have your custom voice detection, you can have a real-time speech, you can also have object detection from a video model. So there's, like, plenty of other components are already built there. There's, like, thousands of applications. If you want to get more creative, and you want to get more
100xEngineers: inspiration, you can go huggingface.co slash spaces, and you can… here, this is the best example, like, what all things are possible. Every week, they do Space of the Week. Right now, 25th May, these… this is some of the top spaces of the week, and I love this thing. This is the carbon, what they have done. This is the autoregressive Genome Foundation model.
100xEngineers: Which they have built on… on the spaces.
100xEngineers: I think they… there's, like, this one called Long Cat Video Avatar. This is also built on radio.
100xEngineers: Let me see if… I can load this.
100xEngineers: Okay, so as you can see, like, this long cat video avatar 1.5, audio-to-image to video generator, everything built on top of video, sorry, on radio. So this is where you can upload the image,
100xEngineers: And you can upload the audio and the prompt, and it will give you the output back. So, I hope some of you might have already explored this side of Hugging Face when you're doing a comfy UI, but if you have not, I would highly recommend you to check out some of the examples out there, get the, I would say.
100xEngineers: inspiration of, like, what is possible and what is not possible. There are a lot of people who started their journey on radio, by the way. All of these people, now they have converted them into a different website, but,
100xEngineers: like, this… this is like a 3D part of it, where you can upload a video or a set of images to create a 3D constructions. And the best part is all of this is open source, so you can go to the file section, and you can check the app.ui file, and now you understand at least some part of it, that… where the code lives, and where the Gradio part works.
100xEngineers: So, although you might not be able to understand everything, but this is where the Python knowledge compounds over time, and it's okay to, like.
100xEngineers: not…
100xEngineers: be able to understand every part of it, but as I said, like, if you go step by step.
100xEngineers: in the next 3 to 4 months, once you build multiple examples, there would be a time where you can look at any of these applications, and, like, you can just, like, understand at least a part of it, what it's doing under the hood, and then you can make changes to it, right? Whatever things you want to build. Let's say you want to make tweaks to this, tweak this part, and there's, like.
100xEngineers: tons of open source and free examples which are out there, and you can, like, build on top of it. So that's… that's the whole beauty of it. So that's a whole new world as well. You can go into this as a rabbit hole.
100xEngineers: But I'll take a pause on this lecture right now, and as I said, like, the three exercises for all of you, one is…
100xEngineers: Read this tutorial, build your first chatbot, but before building that, make sure you have performed the exercise, which we have done. So you have taken your discovery exercise, defined the input and output.
100xEngineers: And I… as of now, I said, like, find one particular use case where you can… you can use chat as the interface, and then go read about this article, implement it.
100xEngineers: Try to do it locally first, because you guys all have done it on the Hugging Face spaces from the web. Try to do it locally. To do it locally, you need to install Python and editor. I would recommend cursor as an editor. If you have something else, you can do that.
100xEngineers: And once you finish this, do let me know. You can share it on the assignments channel on the Discord. In the next office hour, I'll tell your mentors that this is what we have done, so we can discuss more about this. If you have any, like, doubts, or maybe something which you're not able to do in this lecture today, you can drop in the chat. If you have a debugging request, I would recommend you to, like, post on the Discord as a support ticket, so I can watch it.
100xEngineers: Take a screenshot of the error which you're facing, post it there. Me and my mentors will try to, like, help you there. But if you have any questions, you can drop in the chat. If you don't have any questions, this is the end of the lecture, and yeah, I'll see you tomorrow. Tomorrow, we're gonna start the API part, and the next week, we're gonna implement it, so by the end of, like, next two lectures, we'll have our backend and the front-end ready.
100xEngineers: And, yeah, I'm excited for that, so…
100xEngineers: Indajeet, I think I have, mentioned this… I'll try to, like, upload…
100xEngineers: the images, separately. I think the last image which I shared with my team was of the entire whiteboard, but I'm… I keep,
100xEngineers: Sharing everything in the resource channel here as well.
100xEngineers: So…
100xEngineers: So I've shared, like, some of the images here. If you can tell me that if this is not helpful, then I'll be happy to, like, share, like, a whole link. The only problem with the links in ExcitedRaw is that it sometimes just doesn't capture the images after a point, especially on the free version of the shareable whiteboard.
100xEngineers: So that's why it's not most reliable. I try to, like, keep the pictures for it.
100xEngineers: But let me know if this is a right resolution for you, otherwise I'll, yeah, I'll try to, like, find another way to share this.
100xEngineers: Yes, Gaurav, I think, I'm not sure, like, why didn't you receive the recording, but the lectures are uploaded,
100xEngineers: I'll ask my team to maybe share the exact step-by-step process to how to find these lectures. So if, like, somebody from Team 100x
100xEngineers: you can send Gaurav these steps, it'll be easier.
100xEngineers: Personal recommendation for books and resources.
100xEngineers: Yeah, good question. I… I keep, like, updating the reading list for 100X. Right now, I have certain things which I'm reading. Maybe I'll share it, like, and I try to, like, categorize it based on different areas, like the…
100xEngineers: general reading, something related to technology, something related to what we are doing every week.
100xEngineers: Yeah, but thanks for, like, sharing it out. I think, yeah, that's… that's something which would be helpful, so I'll try to organize these recommendations based on the categories. We'll upload that, Tanishk.
100xEngineers: As of now, I would recommend you, first thing is, like, if you can read as much about Gradio right now, I think it's gonna be easier. And, especially if you're a beginner, just make sure you know two things, like, for this weekend, Python and Gradio.
100xEngineers: Like, if you don't know what Python, just finish the big binary, like, focus on that. If you need more help,
100xEngineers: there's, like, Free CodeCamp for Python, there's a lot of resources for Python already out there, Code Academy is there, so you can, like, try it out.
100xEngineers: once you have enough understanding of Python, build user interfaces using Gradio, and the best way to actually learn what I say again and again is, like, by building, and by building something which you care about, and that's why the whole
100xEngineers: Exercise in the week one connects here, because if you really care about a problem that you're solving, the observation that you had.
100xEngineers: now you can start thinking that how this lecture fits into the whole equation, because it helps you to build the user interface, which is the first part of the deterministic systems that we are building. And over time, you can, like, connect this with the backend, the database, the LLM, and that gives you, like, a whole probabilistic and deterministic part, which we are discussing. And it… it now… every lecture is basically a proof that you guys are building, like, especially all the folks
100xEngineers: Who are able to, like.
100xEngineers: create and deploy their first chat on the space. This is, like, a proof that you guys are now becoming a builder. It's like one step closer to becoming a builder, where you now have the capability to build your own interfaces.
100xEngineers: not gonna be, like, a really fancy one, but I think it's still a great, great first step. If you go deep into it. I'm sure, like, Gradion itself right now has, like, as I said, like, there's multiple apps which are, like, using… there's one app,
100xEngineers: This was, I think, called, the Uber Wooga of,
100xEngineers: which was Stable Diffusion UI app, which was completely built. The automatic 1111, which was one of the most popular web UI for Stable Diffusion, that was also built on top of Gradio. So, there are already, like, very, popular projects which has used this as their core layer to build their interfaces.
100xEngineers: So, I would say this is, like, something which I have tested as a path, like, after trying multiple things, after doing more intensive, more difficult things first. This is one of the easiest things which I can suggest for anyone who is starting their journey, to do it.
100xEngineers: Warp is cool, but I don't see a need right now, unless until you are somebody who's a developer who already knows what you're doing. If you're somebody who's starting out fresh, I don't recommend it as of now. I'll share some of the material about CLI, Git in the next week's lecture as well.
100xEngineers: maybe, like, after that, once you have some familiarity of, like, how to operate a command line, and why do you need a command line? Because that's a question which I ask a lot, right? Whenever somebody asks me, like, what do you think about a tool? The question is, why do we need a tool? What is the problem that the tool is gonna solve? So…
100xEngineers: VAP is a CLI, like, it's an AI CLI tool, so it's…
100xEngineers: it's basically helping a lot of people who are operating on CLI, but if you're not operating on CLI, then…
100xEngineers: I won't recommend it, as of now.
100xEngineers: what all need to be done by this module, to my GenAI project, user interface is not needed, I think.
100xEngineers: I didn't get your question. Can you describe this question once again?
100xEngineers: I still use JetPain PyCharm for my development for a long time, just want to know if I have to switch to Agent AID collector, so not needed, Vinod, or Vinodhini. Yeah.
100xEngineers: if you want to use a new ID, and if you're okay, you can definitely switch, but it's not a mandatory requirement, right? If you're comfortable with JetBrains and PyCharm, you can still perform all the exercises there. The only feature which I'm gonna use here and there sometimes is the ask feature, or maybe the chat feature.
100xEngineers: to explain things, which you can also, like, find extensions in JetBrain, right?
100xEngineers: like, I tell you, like, my recommendation is Cursor, because I've been using Cursor when Cursor launched, and it's been, like, almost now three years, I think 2 and a half years, actually. So I have, like, a bias toward it, but I know, like, there are much better applications out there for different use cases. You can use anti-gravity, you can use set brains.
100xEngineers: I… yeah, as I said, like, I would not, again, put this as a hard requirement, right?
100xEngineers: Omar, whatever I shared you, this is exactly relevant to what you're saying.
100xEngineers: So, you need to understand the interface, what is the interface that you're choosing, what are the inputs and outputs. So, if you can send me these two things, the hypothesis, first thing which I need from Omar, if you want me to help you, and this is for everybody as well, if you want me to help you about, like, whatever app you're building, what I need…
100xEngineers: Is the discovery document, which we'll generate after running the file.
100xEngineers: Because if you're building something, I'm assuming that you might have some observation, a problem statement that you have found, and you have built a hypothesis around it, which can be falsifiable, because if it is not falsifiable, then
100xEngineers: It's not a hypothesis, it's a religion, right? And I… unfortunately, I don't work with religions, I work with only problem statements. So if you can send me these two things, one is your hypothesis document, and another one is the… the plan, what you're building.
100xEngineers: And the…
100xEngineers: input and output, what you have described, exactly the same format, what we have just discussed today, like, what is the ideal input, what is the ideal output for your application? I would be able to give you much better inputs. So this is the same applicable for Omar.
100xEngineers: I'll take a whole session about GitHub Jinkees, so don't worry about that. I'll try to cover all of these things there, because I know GitHub is, like, a very overwhelming topic for a lot of people, so I have a lecture planned for this, and I have some materials as well.
100xEngineers: Again, Yovraj and anyone who is, like, asking me these questions, I don't teach with tools, I teach with principles, so…
100xEngineers: No, I won't be able to give you the tool-specific answer. In fact, I don't use Langchain myself.
100xEngineers: And, anything which I need, I try to, like, again, form my own hypothesis around it, build the principles around it. We don't need to use all of this thing. In fact, like, the radio is also something which I'm using because I don't want to, like, add another set of restrictions for all of you that
100xEngineers: People need to learn a new language and a new tool to build a user interface.
100xEngineers: Hence, like, we're trying to, like, take an existing, like, UI. And you'll find this… like, reasoning…
100xEngineers: in… in the areas where… which is basically not the core focus of the cohort, right? But whatever is the core part, for example, like, solving the problem of LLM hallucination, solving the problem of RAG, solving the problem of, like, LLM fine-tuning, all of these things, including, like, building the whole system design, which is a core skill that we need, and what we need to teach, and what we need to learn, all of these, we're gonna take the first principle route, and
100xEngineers: will not talk about tools at all, right? In fact, with RRAG, with fine-tuning, and all of these things, I won't share you exact tools. I will… I'll share, like, the principle, and I'll show you, like, the exact step-by-step
100xEngineers: playbook to build your own tools from scratch, and in fact, I think by end of this whole module.
100xEngineers: some of you would be able to build your own tools. I don't know how many of you follow 0-200X Engineers Challenge right now, but if you are following it, there's a person in Cohort 4, his name is Varun, Varun Nisrani.
100xEngineers: he has built his own NPM package about an agent swarm, like a multi-agent architecture, because he learned all the same principles, and he found out that for his problem statement.
100xEngineers: there was no clear framework out there. Like, Langching was not solving the problem, Langroof was not solving the problem. Like, all the tools which exist in the market.
100xEngineers: on the problem that he was facing. They were not solving that, and it was just increasing the overall token cost. So he ended up, like, applying the same principles and built his own agentic framework, and which basically got, like, I think, some…
100xEngineers: thousand plus hits on the NPM when he launched it. So that is… that is what I believe, right? Like, in the age of AI, I don't think that tool-based thinking really works, so…
100xEngineers: Yeah, I would request you to also, like, think about it from that lens.
100xEngineers: I'll take one last question, and then I'll take a leave, because I have a hard stop right now.
100xEngineers: How was your first experience when you started coding? What made you stick to it? Because I'm doing it again after 2 years and still kind of boring. As I said, like, Tanish, the best way to actually do it, it's… is a motivation problem, right? If you can find something which is worth…
100xEngineers: doing. In this case, like, the problem which I'm trying to solve, through the RF experiment is… is worth doing because there is a business angle to it, and there's also, like, an emotional angle to it, because it's a problem statement, which I have seen multiple times. And I deliberately picked that problem statement because
100xEngineers: I know that if I end up solving this, it will unlock a huge opportunity for me. So that's the same thing for you, right? If you can find the kind of problem statement that
100xEngineers: Can motivate you itself.
100xEngineers: learning code to solve that problem becomes, like, much more easy, because if you just learn code for the sake of learning code, I know that…
100xEngineers: even I feel that, like, because I tried it and it didn't work, so that's the best approach, like, find a problem statement which is worth solving for you, which can unlock maybe a potential outcome, and then you use code, just like the same way how we did today, and will continue for the next upcoming lectures.
100xEngineers: On Discord, ohm. So, Om, you can send me on Discord. Cool, guys, I think that's most of the questions I had. I'll… If I miss any question, you can, again.
100xEngineers: put it on the Discord thread. If you… I think some people were facing issues in the Gradio part, you can just, like, send a screenshot of the error which you were facing. I'll try to take a look at the support ticket after this, but until then, I'll see you soon, and we're gonna start APIs tomorrow, so continue with this, follow the lecture, and
100xEngineers: Keep building, I'll see you soon. Good night, guys. Bye-bye.